## **ROSHNA VAKKEEL**

# **Junior Full Stack Software Developer**

vakkeel.roshna@gmail.com • +0049 17680599495• Berlin Linkedin: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/roshna-vakkeel/">https://www.linkedin.com/in/roshna-vakkeel/</a> Personal website: <a href="https://roshnavakkeel.github.io/Resume/">https://roshnavakkeel.github.io/Resume/</a>

#### **Executive Summary**

Junior Software Developer with a Diploma in Full stack Software Development from the Code Institute and a Scientist with 10+ years of research and interdisciplinary project management experience. I am now eager to gain entry into the tech industry into an exciting development team where I can develop and contribute my unique creative, problem-solving, critical and analytical thinking skills.

### **Education**

Sep 2022–Mar 2023 Diploma in Full Stack Software Development

Specialization: Advanced Frontend

Code Institute - Dublin, Ireland (Credit: University of West of Scotland)

Aug 2007–Apr 2014 Doctor of Philosophy (PhD) in Chemistry

National Chemical Laboratory (NCL), Pune, India

Aug 2005–Jun 2007 Masters of Science (MSc) in Organic Chemistry

University of Pune, India

Aug 2002–Jun 2005 Bachelors of Science (BSc) in Chemistry

Abeda Inamdar College, University of Pune, India

#### **Technical Skillset**

Programming Languages: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Python

Libraries/Frameworks: React, Django, Bootstrap, React-Bootstrap, Django-REST, Pandas

Database Technology: Postgres-SQL
Data Formats: JSON, CSV

Communication Protocols: APIs, REST, HTTP

Development Workflow: Git (Version control), GitHub (Hosting), VSCode (IDE , Editing),

Heroku (PaaS, to deploy and manage apps), Markdown (READMe texts)

App Development Platforms: Mendix (SaaS, low-code platform to develop mobile/web apps)

Web Design Tools: Chrome DevTools, Lighthouse, Balsamiq, Lucidchart

## **Portfolio projects**

• **Be Inspired** - A social media App to connect like minded people who wish to look at the bright side and can also spread positivity to those who seek it through their inspirations.

**Technologies Used** - HTML5, CSS with React-Bootstrap, JavaScript, React (Front End) and, Python, Django-REST framework (Back End) along with Heroku for hosting website.

GitHub: https://github.com/RoshnaVakkeel/be-inspired-pp5-ci

Live Site: https://be-inspired-pp5-ci.herokuapp.com/

• **Little Learner's Lab Logs** - A website where curious kids of all ages can explore, create activity logs and also post fun science experiments that can be performed even at home.

**Technologies Used** - HTML5, CSS with Bootstrap, Python, Django framework, Postgres-SQL DB, Cloudinary for media management, Heroku for hosting website.

GitHub: <a href="https://github.com/RoshnaVakkeel/Little\_Learners\_Lab\_Logs">https://github.com/RoshnaVakkeel/Little\_Learners\_Lab\_Logs</a>

Live Site: <a href="https://little-learners-lab-logs.herokuapp.com/">https://little-learners-lab-logs.herokuapp.com/</a>

• myLab Data Manager – A lab chemical inventory parsing and searching software.

**Technologies Used** - Python, Pandas Library and Heroku for hosting website.

GitHub: <a href="https://github.com/RoshnaVakkeel/myLab\_Data\_Manager">https://github.com/RoshnaVakkeel/myLab\_Data\_Manager</a>

Live Site: <a href="https://mylab-data-manager.herokuapp.com/">https://mylab-data-manager.herokuapp.com/</a>

• **Chem Meets Codes** – A website that compares computational chemistry evolution with progress of programming languages.

Technologies Used - HTML5, CSS3.

GitHub: <a href="https://github.com/RoshnaVakkeel/Chem\_Meets\_Codes">https://github.com/RoshnaVakkeel/Chem\_Meets\_Codes</a> Live Site: <a href="https://roshnavakkeel.github.io/Chem\_Meets\_Codes/">https://roshnavakkeel.github.io/Chem\_Meets\_Codes/</a>

Chem Around Us – A quiz based on chemistry that surrounds us.

**Technologies Used** - HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript.

GitHub: <a href="https://github.com/RoshnaVakkeel/Chem\_Around\_Us">https://github.com/RoshnaVakkeel/Chem\_Around\_Us</a> Live Site: <a href="https://roshnavakkeel.github.io/Chem\_Around\_Us/">https://roshnavakkeel.github.io/Chem\_Around\_Us/</a>

#### Certifications

- MENDIX Rapid Developer Certification, Certificate No. 37687 3<sup>rd</sup> July 2022
- Certification Course on Information Technology (A<sup>+</sup> Grade), Department of Computer Science, Abeda Inamdar College, University of Pune, India – 2004-2005.
- Certification Course on Patents for Scientists and Engineers 7<sup>th</sup> -14<sup>th</sup> Feb 2014, IP Facilitation Center (IPFACE), NCL Innovation Park, Pune, India.

## **Work Experience**

Jul 2014-Nov 2018

#### **Post-doctoral Research Associate**

Max-Planck Institute for Polymer Chemistry, Mainz, Germany & INM – Leibniz Institute for New Materials, Saarbrücken, Germany.

- Designed, synthesized and characterized photoprotected amino acids and medicinal compounds to develop latent biologically active molecules for projects based on regenerative therapies.
- Gained technical expertise on experimentation, analysis, data collection and further studies. Maintained safety data sheets for chemicals, synthesized compounds etc., and GMP guidelines.
- Supervised and trained PhD, project students and CTAs.

#### **Research Experience**

**Postdoctoral Tenure:** "Design, Synthesis and Cell Studies of Phototriggerable Bioactive Selective Integrin Antagonists, VEGF mimics, and Actin Inhibitors to attain Spatiotemporal Control of Cellular Adhesion, Migration and Proliferation on Biomaterials"

**PhD Tenure (2007 - 2014):** "Design and Development of Synthetic Oligomers with Heterogeneous Backbones Featuring  $\alpha/\beta$ -conjugated Building Blocks"

- Preparation of budget proposals for projects, procurement of material and management of inventory
- Collaborate and co-ordinate meetings with cross-functional experts from various scientific disciplines
- Prepare SDS, SOPs for laboratory instruments, and follow good laboratory practices
- · Writing, editing, and proofreading scientific manuscripts following scientific writing guidelines
- Handle scientific structure elucidation software ChemDraw, PyMOL, MERCURY (crystal structure),
   Molecular modelling techniques Schrödinger software.
- Presented in several national and international conferences 12 poster and 5 oral presentations.
- Published manuscripts in high impact journals 13 publications in WILEY-VCH, ACS, RSC, journals with a total of over 490 citations, including *Nature* (IF: 49.96). As Author Name: Roshna V. Nair. <a href="https://scholar.google.com/citations?user=uJ58rfgAAAAJ&hl=en">https://scholar.google.com/citations?user=uJ58rfgAAAAJ&hl=en</a>

#### **Voluntary Activities**

• Guest Editor, Gels, MDPI (Nov 2021–Present)

Special Issue (SI) on "Functional Hydrogels for Biomedical Applications" – Soon to be published <a href="https://www.mdpi.com/journal/qels/special">https://www.mdpi.com/journal/qels/special</a> issues/functional hydrogels biomedical)

- Defined summary, scope and agenda to set up SI website.
- Prepared prospective authors list, sent out invites, managed, scrutinized, and oversaw submissions, and as per ethical and editorial standards, made final decisions on manuscripts.
- Reviewer Journal of Food and Drug Analysis (Sciencedirect), Nutrition (Elsevier) since 2015

#### **Awards/ Memberships**

- 2009 2012: Senior Research Fellowship (SRF) by CSIR, India
- 2007 2009: Junior Research Fellowship (JRF) by CSIR, India
- 2014: NCL Research Foundation- NANAI NATU AWARD 2013, Citation Awarded
- 2004 2005: Member of Exploratory (Intercollegiate Scientific Educational Organization)
- 2003 –2005: Member of National Service Scheme (Empowerment of women in rural area)

#### **Transferable Skills**

- Critical and analytical thinking, data analysis, interpretation, logical-reasoning, and problem-solving
- Effective communication, interpersonal and presentation skills
- Co-ordinating and collaborating across different teams, meeting deadlines, and managing resources.
- Diligence, composure, patience and time management

#### **Additional Information**

- English (Native), German (Intermediate), Hindi (Native), Malayalam (Native)
- Special Interests: Music, learning languages, Yoga, travelling, intercultural events